Guide to the Nathaniel Tarn Papers, ca. 1939-2000 M1132
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Literary Correspondence
  - Subseries C. British Authors Single Correspondence Files
    - Middleton, Christopher (Box 28, Folder 4)
      10 als, 2 tls, 4 handwritten postcards; 17 pages & 6 pages of original ts poems; large tls proof of EastGerman poems translated by CM, 1964, inscribed; 1963-
    - Mottram, Eric (Box 28, Folder 5)
      7 tls, 1 typed postcard; 12 pp. & King's College, London materials on Mottram archive, 1972-75.
    - Raworth, Tom (Box 28, Folder 6)
      7 als, 3 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 10 pages, 1967-
    - Selerie, Gavin (Box 28, Folder 7)
      3 als; 17 tls, 6 handwritten postcards; 34 pp., 1985-
    - Silkin, Jon (Box 28, Folder 8)
      8 als, 2 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 12 pages with materials on Stand magazine, Northern House Books, London Times obituary, etc, 1962-74.
    - Smith, John (Box 28, Folder 9)
      6 als, 7 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 18 pages & hand-corrected poem by JS - an early helper of NT, early 1960s.
    - Smith, Ken (Box 28, Folder 10)
      5 als, 6 tls, 14 pages, 1965-83.
    - Tomlinson, Charles (Box 28, Folder 11)
      18 als; 18 pages & several pp. relating to Vallejo publication, plus 1 tls from Mme Georgette Vallejo interdicting Cape publication, plus 4 tls from Stallworthy, John at Oxford U. Press, 1967-69.
    - Wesker, Arnold [1 of 3] (Box 28, Folder 12)
      24 als; 10 tls; 54 handwritten postcards; 62 pages, and much copy including: original photo of AW & Martha Crewe by J. Svoboda; photo of AW & grandchild; photo of AW as hon. D.Phil.; 3 pp. holograph notes by NT on AW talks; 11 pp. report "That's Venezuela," with handwritten corrections; 1 drawing, Havana, 1966; ms letter & poem re kitchen employment, aetat 24; 9pp. photocopy "Accepting the Unacceptable," 1974 inscribed; 5 pp. mimeographed text "Steiner's Hitler Got it Wrong," with handwritten corrections; 8 pp. inscribed text "La Miseria de non-essere poeta," 1975-76 inscribed; 4 pp. photocopy of "Open Letter to an Assassin;" "The House," Encounter reprint 11/66 inscribed; The Jewish Quarterly, VII,1, 1959-60; Theater Quarterly, 1971 proof inscribed; Plays International 4/87; programme of "The Friends;" Plymouth Theater playbill opening night of "The Merchant;" other theatrical materials; many cuttings, etc., 1962-; also Wesker, Dusty: 7 als, 15 handwritten postcards, 11 pages, 1980s-90s.
    - Wesker, Arnold [2 of 3] (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Wesker, Arnold [3 of 3] (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - West, Paul (Box 29, Folder 2)
      1 als, 2 tls, 5 handwritten postcards, 1 typed postcard; 4 pages & 6 pp. copy; a photocard "Trucking through the Turks" a "Sky Art Event" with Diane Ackerman, PW and others, 1994-
    - Wevill, David, and Wevill, Assia. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      DW: 5 als, 11 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 26 pages & 12 pp. of photocopied poems & several poems in cuttings, 1958-86;AW: 6 als, 8 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 22 pages; plus 23 ms pp. of NT notes concerning the Sylvia Plath & Assia Wevill (& child of Ted Hughes) suicides, unpublished, plus photos & mementos, 1958-69.
    - White, Kenneth (Box 29, Folder 4)
      62 als, 5 handwritten postcards; 148 pages & ms 3 pp. translation of Breton's "Girasol;" 5 pp. Jargon Paper no. 2, 1965 at time of May 1968 Paris events "On the Cultural Revolution;" 5 pp. mimeo on politics, 19[?]
  - Subseries D. Subseries D. British Authors Group Miscellaneous Correspondence Files
    - Miscellaneous British [1 of 3] (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Adair, Gilbert: 1 als, 2 tls; 3 pages & 6 pp. poetry, 1987-Alexander, Michael: 1 als; 2 pages, 1963.Baybars, Tana: 1 als; 1 page, 1963.Brooke-Rose, Christine: 1 als; 1 page, 1965.Bold, Alan: 2 typed postcards, 1980.Caddell, Rick: 1 tls, 5 handwritten postcards; 1 page & 3 pp. of poetry, 1987-Cicelis, Kaye: 1 als: 1 page, 1973.Cornford, Adam: 1 als; 2 pages, 1971-Fainlight, Ruth: 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages, 1966-7.Fielding, Gabriel: 1 als, 2 tls; 4 pages, 1969.Fonteyn, Margot (dancer): 1 als, 2 pages, 1945.Ghose, Zulfikar: 1 typed postcard, 1965.Grubb, Fred: 1 handwritten postcard, 1 inscribed poem, 1960s.Guedalla, Roger: 3 tls; 4 pages, 1971-3.Hamburger, Michael: 2 als; 6 pages, 1963-4.Harwood, Lee: 3 tls; 1 handwritten postcard; 3 pages, 1969.Hignett, Sean: 1 als; 1 page, 1970.Hinde, Thomas: 1 als; 1 tls; 2 pages, 1962.Hobsbaum, Philip: 1 tls; 1 page, 1962.Jennings, Elizabeth: 1 typed postcard, 1960s.Johnson, B.S.: 1 als, 1 ts; 2 pages & 1 circular, 1963.Josephs, Wilfrid (composer): 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages, 1966.Kerrigan, Anthony: 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 3 pages, 1974.
    - Miscellaneous British [2 of 3] (Box 29, Folder 6)
      King, Basil: 1 als; 1 page, 1992.Lewis, Cecil Day [Day-Lewis]: 1 als; 1 page, 1968.Longville, Tim: 1 als, 5 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 9 pages, 1971-3.Lowenstein, Tom: 3 als, 3 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 7 pages & a prospectus, 1981-7.Mackmin, Michael: 1 als, 2 tls; 2 pages, 1970-2.Mairowitz, David: 1 tls; 1page, 1986.Mead, Matthew: 2 als, 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 4 pages & copies of contracts, etc, 1969.Mitchell, Adrian: 1 tls; 1 page & prospectus for a U.S. tour, 1970.Nuttall, Jeff: 1 typed form with ms note, 1969.Nye, Robert: [8 tls, not originally listed by Tarn]O'Brien, Edna 1 tls; 1 page, 1965.Oran, Neill: 4 page ts poem, inscribed, 1975.Paolozzi, Eduardo (painter): 1 tls, 1 page, 1968.Pinter, Harold: 1 typed postcard, 1968.Reynolds, Tim: 1 tls; 1 page, 1973.Robinson, Ian: 3 als, 1 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 5 pages, 1985-
    - Miscellaneous British [3 of 3] (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Rudolph, Anthony: 3 als, 4 tls, 4 handwritten postcards; 11 pages, 1969-Russell, Peter: 16 page mimeograph on archive fire in Italy with poems, 1990.Salkey, Andrew: 1 tls; 1 page, 1970.Schmidt, Michael: 1 tls; 1 page & 2 pp. of praise for Cape Editions, 1973.Sillitoe, Alan: 5 als; 5 pages, 1960s-70s (*) [not found].Sinclair, Andrew: 1 handwritten postcard, 1963.Symons, Jean: 1 als, 2 handwritten postcards; 2 pages & typed poems with corrections, 1963.Simpson, Joan Murray: 1 tls; 1 page, 1983.Thomas, D.M.: 1 als;1 page, 1968.Tonks, Rosemary: 1 als, 2 handwritten postcards; 3 pages, 1963-70.Turnbull, Gael: 1 als; 1 page, 1964.Walker, Ted: 1 als; 4 pages, 1964.Whigham, Peter: [1 p. handwritten note, not originally listed by Tarn]White, Ivan: 3 als; 4 pages, 1964.Williams, J. Hartley: 1 typed postcard, 1991.
  - Subseries E. French Authors Single Correspondence Files
    - Auxemery, Jean Paul (Box 30, Folder 2)
      2 als, 8 tls, 12 handwritten postcards; 24 pages & 27 pp. copy on Charles Olson, 8 pp. ts of poems,
    - Barthes, Roland (Box 30, Folder 3)
      2 handwritten notes, 1969
    - Breton, Andre (Box 30, Folder 4)
      1 printed questionnaire on magic, signed and addressed to NT as member of Surrealist group, 1955 plus 1951Surrealist Movement documents: 17 pp. mimeo from Henri Pastoureau on The Carrouges Affair; 1 p. mimeofrom AB & Benjamin Peret: Letter to Pastoureau; mimeo letter from Maurice Henry to AB; 1 p. mimeo from Pastoureau to the Group; 3 pp. mimeo from Patrick Waldberg to the S. group; 1 p. holograph by Henri Seigle regarding the Carrouges affair; collection of contemporary cuttings on the death of AB, including tributes by Marcel Duchamp, Philippe Soupault, etc.
    - Butor, Michel (Box 30, Folder 5)
      2 als: 2 pages, 1963-8.
    - Deguy, Michel [1 of 2] (Box 30, Folder 6)
      99 als, 11 postcards, 170 pages & copy & NRF[New French Review] Gallimard files, Colloquium papers, 1963-
    - Deguy, Michel [2 of 2] (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Duchamp, Marcel (Artist) (Box 30, Folder 8)
      3 als; 4 pages, 1951-68.
    - Ponge, Francis (Box 30, Folder 9)
      1 als; 2 pages, 1967.
    - Supervielle, Jules (Box 30, Folder 10)
      2 als; 4 pages, 1949.
  - Subseries F. French Group Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous French [1 of 2] (Box 31, Folder 1)
      ALBIACH, ANNE MARIE: 1 als; 1 tls; 2 pages, 1966-67.CARROUGES, Michel: 8 als, 1 tls; 20pages & funeral notice, 1960-75.Couturier, Michel: 4 tls; 4 pages, 1966-67.Di Manno, Yves: 7 als, 2 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 14 pages & copy of NT translations of Di Manno's Cambodian poems, 1991-92.Emmanuel, Pierre: 1 tls, 1 typed postcard; 1 page, 1967.Faye, Jean Pierre: 1 handwritten postcard, 1 "Pere Duchesne" letterpress issue, 1967.Gaspard, Lorand: 1 als; 1 handwritten postcard; 1 page, 1968-74.Guillevic: 3 original ts poems inscribed, 1967.Guilloux, Louis: 1 als; 1 page, 1965.Jabes, Edmond: 1 handwritten postcard, 1983.Krea, Henri: 1 handwritten postcard, 1965.Oster, Pierre, 1 als; 1 page, 1962.Pleynet, Marcelin: 1 handwritten postcard, 1 typed postcard, 1981.
    - Miscellaneous French [2 of 2] (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Roche, MAURICE: 1 handwritten postcard, n.d.ROYET-Journoud, CLAUDE: 8 als, 6 postcards 18 pp, 1966-74.SEGALEN, YVON: 2 ALS; 3 pp., 1991-.
  - Subseries G. European Authors Single Correspondence Files
    - Gergely, Agnes (Hungary) (Box 31, Folder 3)
      6 als, 8 tls, 3 handwritten post cards; 32 pages & 20 pp. of mutual translations with annotations & corrections NT/AG/NT, 1992-
    - Ibsen, Arni (Iceland) (Box 31, Folder 4)
      7 tls, 3 handwritten postcards; 20 pages & 40 pp. of Ibsen and of NT in Icelandic translation.
    - LACERDA, ALBERTO De (Portugal) (Box 31, Folder 5)
      16 letters [als and tls], 8 postcards [handwritten]; 35 pages & copy including: 5 original ts translation of Pessoa with handwritten notes by AL; 2 original photos of AL & NT in Boston; ms notes by NT on AL, 1957-72
    - Nicolai, Giulia (Italy) (Box 31, Folder 6)
      8 als, 2 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 27 pages, 1994-6
    - Sanesi, Roberto (Italy) (Box 31, Folder 7)
      3 als, 30 tls, 7 handwritten postcards; 37 pp and Sanesi's work on NT's The Beautiful Contradictions (published Milan) and letters from Arturo Schwartz (inter alia Duchamp specialist), 1968-76
    - SARTORIUS, JOACHIM & GRAF-SARTORIUS, Karin (Germany) (Box 31, Folder 8)
      4 als, 6 tls, 6 postcards; 19 pages & 31 pp. of mutual translations NT/JS/NT with annotations & corrections, 1992-
    - Tart, Indrek (Estonia) (Box 32, Folder 1)
      4 als, 6 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 13 pages & copy, 1992-
    - Ten Berge, Hans (Netherlands) [1 of 3] (Box 32, Folder 2)
      25 als, 43 tls, 36 handwritten postcards, 1 ts; 86 pages & much copy including: 24 pp. carbon of "From: A Case of Delusion;" 19 pp. carbon of "Autostrade;" 4 pp. original ts of "Lubeck;" 9 pp. photocopy of "Texaaanse Elegien;" original poems for NT; 12 pp. photocopy of HTB poems in French translation; photocopy of Chicago Review poems of HTB in English; large amount of material about NT into Dutch; correspondence with Prof. E.M. Beekman of U. Mass, Amherst about HTB and his own work 1961-
    - Ten Berge, Hans (Netherlands) [2 of 3] (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Ten Berge, Hans (Netherlands) [3 of 3] (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Subseries H. European Authors Group Miscellaneous Correspondence Files
    - Miscellaneous European (Box 32, Folder 5)
      AMICHAI, YEHUDA (Israel): 1 als; 1 page, 1968.CEDRINS, P. (Latvia): 2 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages, 1994-DOMIN, HILDE (Germany): 6 tls, 1 ts, 11 pages, 1965-66.DRAGOMOSHENKO, ARKADY (Russia): 1 tls; 2 pages, 1991-HARDER, UFE (Denmark): 5 tls; 7 pages, 1966-67.HERSBERG, J (Netherlands): 3 als, 1 typed postcard; 6 pages, 1975.HOLUB, MIROSLAV (Czechoslovakia): 2 tls, 1 ts; 2 pages, 1971-76.JONSON, UWE (Germany): 1 tls; 2 pages, 1968.KANTOR, PETR (Hungary): 4 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 4 pages & 12 pp. copy and poems, 1991-POPA, VASKO (Yugoslavia): 1 handwritten postcard, 1968.ROKEAH, DAVID (Israel): 4 als, 1 tls, 3 handwritten postcards; 4 pages, 1964-65.SACHS, NELLY (Germany): 1 handwritten postcard, 1966.SCHIERBEEK, BERNDT (Netherlands): 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages & broadside, "de deur" signed, 1980.SPAZIANI, MARIA LUISA (Italy): 1 handwritten postcard, 1969.VAES, GUY (Belgium): 1 ALS; 2 pages & 28 pp. ts on Antwerp.VASOVIC, N. (Yugoslavia): 1 tls, 1 page, 1993.VILJARMSSON, T. (Iceland): 2 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 7 pages, 1974-5.WYDENBRUCK, NORA (Austria, friend & biographer of Rilke): 1 tls, 1967.
    - Miscellaneous European: African authors (Box 32, Folder 6)
      MPHALELE, E.: 1 als, 1 page, 1976.SOYINKA, W.: no. of letters, 1960s [not found]
  - Subseries I. Latin American Authors Single Correspondence Files
    - Aridjis, Homero (Mexico) (Box 32, Folder 7)
      3 als, 4 tls, 2 handwritten postcards, 3 typed postcards; 8 pages & 3 pp. of NT translations of HA; original ts of two poems by HA; "The Morelia Declaration, 1991", 1965-89.
    - Lam, Wilfredo (Painter, Cuba) (Box 32, Folder 8)
      1 tls; 1 page with pencil drawing 1952
    - Manjarrez, Hector (Mexico) (Box 32, Folder 9)
      7 als, 26 tls, 3 handwritten postcards, 1 typed postcards; 66 pages & copy including: 14 pp. carbon with handwritten corrections 1969; 1 p. poem dedicated to NT; 5 pp. ts of notes inscribed; cuttings of texts inscribed, 1969-
    - Neruda, Pablo (Chile) (Box 33, Folder 1)
      5 als, 2 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 8 pages & 11 pp. copy; 4 original photographs of Oxford Mail & Times of PN in doctoral attire; 6 pp. typed list of contents by Neruda for NT's volume of Selected Poems of PN; 3 pp. carbon of PN on Watergate plus English translation; Menu, Park Hotel, Bled, Yugoslavia with some Czech signatures & Miroslav Holub list guests: Pound, Olson, Neruda, Alberti, Bachmann, Asturias, Quasimodo; Spender, etc.; several pages of Cape correspondence with PN; PN hologr. list of poems to be read at London Festival Hall 12.67; correspondence with New York Y about Neruda readings; 1 letter from Matilde N after death of PN; 1 tls from Prof. J.M.Cohen; photocopies of Neruda texts of quotes; many cuttings, 1965-73.
    - Paz, Octavio (Mexico) (Box 33, Folder 2)
      4 als, 28 tls, 3 handwritten postcards; 47 pages & copy including: 4 pp. ts list of Marcel Duchamp works by OP, 1968; 8 pp. pamphlet on Mallarme from Dialogos, 1968, inscribed; Program of Paz Festival at Palacio de Bellas Artes with international caste; Program of Paz reading at New York Y, 10.43; correspondence with translators; many cuttings and documents, (Paz known since 1950 at Surrealist Group, Paris) 1966-
    - Rojas, Gonzalo (Chile) (Box 33, Folder 3)
      1 als; 1 page & 27 pp. of poems with notes and comments, 1989.
  - Subseries J. Latin American Authors Group Miscellaneous Correspondence Files
    - Miscellaneous Latin American (Box 33, Folder 4)
      ACOSTA,JUVENAL (Mexico): 1 tls; 1 page, 1986.ArMAND, OCTAVIO (Cuba): 1 tls; 2 pages, 1971.BRACHO, CORAL (Mexico): 1 als; 2 pages, 1984.CISNEROS, ANToNIO (Peru): 1 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 3 pages, 1968-74.DeLaCRUZ, VICTOR (Mexico): 1 tls; 1 page, 1989.FERNANDEZ, PABLO ARMANDO (Cuba): 1 als; 1 page, 1968.RODRIGUEZ FEO, JOSE (Cuba): 1 als, 1 tls; 2 pages, 1968.SANCHEZ, ALBERTO RUIZ (Mexico): 2 handwritten postcards, 1993.SEGOVIA, TOMAS (Mexico): 2 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 6 pages & documents, 1971-SUARDIAZ, LUIS (Cuba): 2 tls; 2 pages; 1 poem inscribed, 1969. TRUJILLO, RENATO (Chile): 1 tls; 1 page, 1990.ULACIA, MANUEL (Mexico): 1 als; 1 tls; 3 pages, 1994.VICUNA, CECILIA (Chile): 2 als; 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages & 10 pp, copy of Martin Adan poems & brochures, 1990-
  - Subseries K. Australian Authors Single Correspondence Files
    - HEMMENSLEY, Kris (Box 33, Folder 5)
      4 als, 12 tls; 40 pages & 10pp. ts poetry. 1971-
    - Stoneking, William (Box 33, Folder 6)
      1 als; 1 p., see also Scripts file (*) 1996- [missing?]
    - Tranter, John (Box 33, Folder 7)
      1 als, 4 tls; 1 typed postcard; 5 pages, 1993-
  - Subseries L. Literary Critics: Individual and Group Correspondence Files
    - Altieri, Charles (Modern Poetry, U. Washington) (Box 33, Folder 8)
      3 tls; 4 pages & 42 pp. photocopied ts "The Powers & Limits of Oppositional Postmodernism, 1987"; handwritten notes by NT on CA and other notes; 1980s.
    - Bartlett, Lee (American Literature, UNM) [1 of 3] (Box 33, Folder 9)
      8 als, 28 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 2 typed postcards; 41 pages and a great deal of copy mostly inscribed, with much description of publishing ventures, including: 26 pp. ts of various poems by LB; 11 pp. photocopy of article on Snyder in Western American Literature, 1982; 2 reprints from American Literary Scholarship for 1981, 1982; Abacus no.5, 9.84: LB; 2 pp. letter to UNM [University of New Mexico], NT for LB; 6 pp. ts of talk with NT for Alb. Journ. 1985; 6 pp. text on Language Poetry controversy; 10 pp. xerox on Everson for the Centen. Rev. & other Everson papers; materials on NT Bibliography by LB and NT's Views from the Weaving Mountain published by LB; 4 pp. letter to Campus Editor re controversy over Santiago Baca, 1991; draft of NT review of Rexroth-Laughlin book, edited by LB, with handwritten notes for Sulfur; correspondence with Schwerner re Norton Anthology; pages of NT phone notes re talks with LB; 5 pp. printout of letter to UNM Press re American Poetry Books Series crisis, 1993; materials from Mary Bartlett (poet); Jennifer Bartlett (poet); Elizabeth Bartlett (artist), see also very large collection in Scripts files; 1960s-.
    - Bartlett, Lee (American Literature, UNM) [2 of 3] (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Bartlett, Lee (American Literature, UNM) [3 of 3] (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Corngold, Stanley (Germanic Languages, Philosophy, Princeton U.) (Box 34, Folder 2)
      1 als, 13 tls, 8 handwritten postcards, 3 typed postcards; 32 pages and copy: 1974-86.
    - Felstiner, John (Neruda, Celan; Jewish Literature, Stanford U.) (Box 34, Folder 3)
      9 als; 16 pages, 1981-
    - Fiedler, Leslie (American Literature, SUNY Buffalo) (Box 34, Folder 4)
      1 als, 1 tls; 2 pages, 1968.
    - Finkelstein, Norman (Modern Poetry, Xavier U) (Box 34, Folder 5)
      1 als; 4 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 8 pages, 1994-
    - Giordano, Fedora [not in Tarn's original listing] (Box 34, Folder 6)
      [2 als; 6 tls, 5 handwritten postcards]
    - Kearns, Cleo McNelly & Kearns, George (Eliot, Derrida, Kristeva / Pound, Rutgers U) [1 of 3] (Box 34, Folder 7)
      29 als, 34 tls, 40 handwritten postcards, 1 typed post card; 150 pages & 13 pp. ts on Kristeva and other copy, 1971
    - Kearns, Cleo McNelly & Kearns, George (Eliot, Derrida, Kristeva / Pound, Rutgers U) [2 of 3] (Box 34, Folder 8)
      29 als, 34 tls, 40 handwritten postcards, 1 typed post card; 150 pages & 13 pp. ts on Kristeva and other copy, 1971-
    - Kearns, Cleo McNelly & Kearns, George (Eliot, Derrida, Kristeva / Pound, Rutgers U) [3 of 3] (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Materassi, Mario (American Literature, Firenze U) (Box 34, Folder 10)
      3 tls, 3 handwritten postcards; 3 pages, 1992-
    - Paul, Sherman (American Literature, Iowa U) (Box 35, Folder 1)
      4 als; 26 tls, 1 handwritten postcard, 1 typed postcard; 67 pages; very long critical letters from NT, 1990-+95.
    - Quartermain, Peter (Modern Poetry, Zukofsky, Oppen, S.Howe, U British Columbia) (Box 35, Folder 2)
      2 als, 5 tls, 6 handwritten postcards; 10 pages and 2 reprints on Zukofsky & Joyce, 1990-
    - Sieburth, Richard (Pound, Modernism; French Literature; NYU): (Box 35, Folder 3)
      6 als, 1 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 13 pages, 1984-
    - Steiner, George (Modern Literature, Cultural Studies, Philosophy, U Geneva) [1 of 2] (Box 35, Folder 4)
      1 als, 28 tls, 2 handwritten postcards, 1 typed postcard; 34 pages & copy including: 7 pp. exchange of letters GS - Chomsky, 1967; 17 pp. Encounter reprint of "The Language Animal," 1969, inscribed; GS notes on meeting with Levi-Strauss; 4 pp. carbon memo on a NT/GS conversation re Adorno; pages of phone talk notes; 1965 copy of letter to Maschler of Cape with fulsome praise of NT's first book; large no. of cuttings, 1965-70.
    - Steiner, George (Modern Literature, Cultural Studies, Philosophy, U Geneva) [2 of 2] (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Watanabe, Shinji (American poetry, Kyoto, U) (Box 35, Folder 6)
      1 als, 3 tls; 4 pages & 14 pp. ts of SW poems in English, 1980s.
    - Ziquing, Zhang (American Poetry, U of Nanjing) (Box 35, Folder 7)
      2 als, 11 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 19 pages & 24 pages of NT teaching to ZZ re the EP-HD-WCW lineage which changed ZZ's huge "History of 20th Century American Poetry (1995- Changchun 1997); some 20 pp., of printouts of ZZ prefaces etc., 1992.
    - Miscellaneous Critic Files (Box 35, Folder 8)
      Brown, Clarence (Russian Studies, Mandelstam); Kermode, Frank (Modern Literature); Matthews, J. (Surrealism);Lang, Frances and Victor [not listed by Tarn]Niranjana, Tejaswini (Raj, Translation Theory); Pargeter, Edith (Czech Lit.); Poulet, Georges (Literature, Philosophy);Rosenthal, M.L. (Modern Poetry); Said, Edward [not listed by Tarn]Urzidil, Johannes (friend of Kafka).Weatherhead, Kingsley [not listed by Tarn]
  - Subseries M. Individual and Group Correspondence Files
    - Amenoff, Gregory (Painter, illustrator of NT's Multitude of One, Grenfell Press) (Box 35, Folder 9)
      5 als, 1 tls, 1 typed postcard; 17 pages & 9 illustr. showannouncements; 1 catalogue; 1990-
    - Berry, William (Painter) (Box 36, Folder 1)
      1 als, 5 handwritten postcard; 5 pages & catalogue with notes, 1988-92.
    - Chappell, Walter (Photographer) (Box 36, Folder 2)
      2 handwritten postcards and vita & other illustrated documents, 1990.
    - Digby, John (Collagist, previously self-proclaimed Pope of English Surrealism; one of NT's oldest friends) [1 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 3)
      90 als, 47 tls, 110 handwritten postcards; 195 pages & copy including: 24 pp. original ts poems; many printed poems; 9 original collages (out of larger collection); 21 original large photos of collage work; others of JD in different settings; large quantity of posters, cards and other illustrations; several reviews; 19 slides of collages; other correspondence including 2 als from Theodore Weiss, 1960s-
    - Digby, John (Collagist, previously self-proclaimed Pope of English Surrealism; one of NT's oldest friends) [2 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Digby, John (Collagist, previously self-proclaimed Pope of English Surrealism; one of NT's oldest friends) [3 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Digby, John (Collagist, previously self-proclaimed Pope of English Surrealism; one of NT's oldest friends) [4 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Dreyblatt, Arnold (Composer) (Box 36, Folder 7)
      1 als, 9 tls, 5 handwritten postcards, 1 typed postcard plus 5 concert announcements and 10 pp. ts announcement of "Whos' Who in Central Europe, 1933," 1990-
    - Hamady, Walter (printer of NT/JR The forest) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      3 tls; 3 pages & 11 pp. of Letterpress items; 2 pp.printout of ironic comments on poetry publishing, 1987-
    - Jacno, Marcel (Typographer, Designer for Shell, Gauloises, Teatre National Populaire etc. etc. designer of NT's very first book "La Legende de St. Germain des Pres") (Box 37, Folder 1)
      8 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 8 pages & 5 mock ups & set of logos for NT small books proposed publishing venture in early 50s (Paris Editions); catalogue of MJ painting show, 1954-+87.
    - Palanker, Robin (Painter) (Box 37, Folder 2)
      2 als, 1 tls, 2 handwritten postcards, 2 typed postcards; 4 pages and many show announcements, 1993-
    - Petersen, Will (Painter) (Box 37, Folder 3)
      4 als, 4 tls, 2 handwritten postcards 2 typed postcards; 15 pages, many re publication of his letterpress mag. Plucked Chicken; illutr. announcements of WP shows, 1977-1987
    - Schrieber, Ilse (Painter, Printer of NT Holderlin poem) (Box 37, Folder 4)
      3 als, 1 handwritten postcard, 1 typed postcard; 3 pages & announcements, 1992-3.
    - Miscellaneous Artist Files (1970s - Present) (Box 37, Folder 5)